## CHEN GABIZON

Tel Aviv, Israel | +972-54-7229096 | chengabizon95@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/ken-gabizon

#### **SUMMARY:**

Full Stack Developer at Zoominfo. Graduated from the IDF's Computing and Cyber Defense Academy at IDF's central computing system unit. 5 years in a major development team at IDF's biggest software house, developed military systems for command and control that were widely used in recent IDF operations.

Dedicated professional with strong analytical and conceptual problem-solving abilities as well as the necessary communication organizational and time management skills to take on any task and exceed expectations.

Good communication and interpersonal skills, ability to perform as part of a team as well as independently.

#### SKILLS:

Languages JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Java

Technologies: Node.js, Angular, Google Cloud, MySQL, MongoDB, Grails, Git

- Ability to coordinated with project managers and quality assurance personnel to ensure top-quality code and assisted with the completion of department-wide project milestones and program objectives
- Strong knowledge and experience with object-oriented programing developing various applications
- Extensive programming experience building complex Web-based applications using Node.js 6.x/8.x/10.x and Angular 4/5/8
- Strong knowledge of SQL, Relational Databases and extensive scripting experience in coding complex queries
- Worked with different methodologies like Waterfall, Scrum and other agile processes

## **EDUCATION:**

**College of Management Academic Studies, The Department of Computer Science** *Bachelor of Science – Computer Science* 

Rishon Lezion, Israel *May 2019* 

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

**Zoom Information Inc.** 

Ra'anana, Israel July 2019 – Present

Full Stack Dev<u>eloper & Team Leader</u>

- Led a team of 3-5 developers in the design and development of the company's inner web portal written in Node.js and Angular 8 replacing the UI and backend layer increasing performance by 200%
- Developed prototype systems and tested code from all developers to uncover and resolve programming issues
- Conducted daily and weekly meetings, constantly receiving feedback for just in time information gathering
- Analyzed and validated program specifications as well as designed and created reliable and reusable code that conformed to department standards and procedures
- Met with department heads and users to gather requirements and scope technical changes
- Developed cross browser, device independent high-quality, high-performance user interfaces, web pages and web forms using Angular 5/8 to enhance UX and increase web traffic

# IDF - C4i Technological Division - Matzpen unit | Chief Sergeant

Tel Aviv, Israel

# Full Stack Developer & Deputy team manager

January 2017 – July 2019

- Led the development team as a deputy team manager, coordinating all team members and actively addressing and resolving team issues
- Designed and implemented interactive Web-based applications to ensure high performance, scalability, security and optimal user experience using Node.js and Angular 4
- Led and managed the training process of 30 junior engineers, preparing a 2 month training course including: lesson plans, exercises and tests, logistics management and delivered multiple frontal lectures
- Wrote SQL stored procedures for achieving better performance, security, data manipulation and querying data for MySQL server dealing with highly sensitive information and cyber warfare threats
- Used Angular 4 to develop a web application for controlling & monitoring IDF combat warehouses being used in IDF
  operations speeding up the deployment, increasing capacity and reducing costs for better field performance

#### Full Stack Developer in a major development team

March 2014 - January 2017

- Involved in a complete life cycle of a software development including requirements gathering, analyzing, design, development, coding, implementation, testing, deployment and maintenance of a project
- Developed high-performance modularized genetic algorithm which considers multiple factors to build and plan training operations procedures involving several divisions increasing efficiency and reducing costs
- Participated in designing and coding of the Presentation Layer, Business Logic Layer and Data Access Layer
- Improved and added new features managing maintenance process of tanks, APC's, and other combat vehicles reducing costs and optimizing performance. Used Git for version control

**OTHER:** Fluent in Hebrew and English